<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Basic Storage :: My Blog Page</title>
    <link>http://localhost:54582/firstcloudjourney/02-basic-storage/index.html</link>
    <description>1. Type of storage:&#xD;1.1 Block storage&#xD;Data is stored on a device in fixed-sized block. Applications and file systems regulate how blocks are accessed, combined and modified. Break up data into blocks and then stores those blocks as separate pieces, each with unique identifier. They are stored wherever it is most efficient. Thus, it can store those blocks across different systems and each block can be configured to work with different operating systems. 1.2 File storage&#xD;File storage is a methodology that help users, applications, and services access data in a shared file system. Data is stored in a hierarchical structure. This structure is similar to a centralized shared network drive in a company where employees store and access files 1.3 Object storage&#xD;Files are stored as objects based on attributes and metadata. Each object consists of data, metadata and an object key. The metadata has information about the data (object size, object purpose and more). The object key is the unique identifier of the object. When you update files in object storage, the entire file object is updated, instead of a piece of a file, as in block storage 2. Use cases&#xD;2.1 Block storage: consistent and low-latency performance&#xD;Hosting database instances: SAP HANA. Oracle, SQL,.. Big data analytics: detach and reattach volumes, resize cluster, persistent, fast storage Enterprise applications: high availability and high durability, IOPS 2.2 Object storage:&#xD;Disaster recovery Data lakes Cloud-native applications 3. AWS core storage services&#xD;Amazon Elastic Block Store (EBS) Amazon Elastic File System (EFS) Amazon Elastic File System (S3) - Amazon EBS: scalable, high-performance block-storage service. - Simple elastic file system, share file data without provisioning or managing storage. - An object storage service with bucket - Designed for Amazon EC2: create volume and attach to EC2 instances. - Well suited to support a broad spectrum of use cases: storage for serverless application, web serving and content management, app dev and testing and database backups. - Bucket is a container for objects - Durable snapshot, 99.99% availability. - EC2, Containers, AWS lambda, servers mount,… - data lakes, websites, mobile app, backup and restore, archive, enterprise app, big data - SSD based: General purpose, Provisioned IOPS. - HDD based: Throughput optimized, Cold. 4. Amazon Simple Storage Solution (S3)&#xD;4.1 Object storage:&#xD;Objects Buckets Regions Keys 4.2 Basic S3 workflow:&#xD;Accept data of all file types Less than 5TB 4.3 Object-level storage:&#xD;When you store an object in a bucket, the combination of a bucket name, key, and version ID uniquely identifies the objects so that you can interact with that object. 4.4 Active and archive storage:&#xD;The two broad categories are active storage and archive storage. Active storage is for data that you use all the time. It also includes data that you access less frequently but it is important that the data can be accessed quickly. Ex web static, backup,… Archive storage is for data that you rarely access but must be maintained. 5. Amazon S3 storage classes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate></lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:54582/firstcloudjourney/02-basic-storage/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
  </channel>
</rss>